Jesús Fabian **Berríos Soto**

RUN 25.681.197-9

SKILLS



PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python, R, bash/shell, Pyspark, PHP, Java, C++

DATABASES

SQL (Spark/Hive/MySQL), NoSQL (Hbase)

MACHINE LEARNING

Regression, Classification, Clustering, Boosting (sklearn)

Neural Networks (keras)

Images, NLP (fastai, pytorch)

NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING

nltk, spacy, genism, pyLDA

COMPUTER VISION

IntroCV, PIL

DATA VISUALIZATION

Python (matplotlib, seaborn, plotly), Tableau

CLOUD COMPUTING

GCP/Azure, individual VMs and Hadoop Cluster. DevOps. DataBricks. Docker.

DATA CAPTURE

API Tweepy,

TELECOM/NETWORKING

QoS, Customer Experience, KPIs/KQIs for mobile and fixed networks Signalling flow analysis Core CS/PS GUL. Comissioning for Servers, Lan Switchs (L2/L3). Tx MW/DWDM. Network Design.

LANGUAGES



- Spanish (Native)
- English (Advanced)

REFERENCES



Adolfo Pierron

Huawei Chile | Smartcare Team Leader

+56 975871307

DATA SCIENTIST – TELECOM. ENG.



+56 9 87225898

jesusfberrios@gmail.com



Av. Manquehue Nte. 966, Santiago



in https://cl.linkedin.com/in/jesusberrios



https://github.com/jesusfberrios

ABOUT ME



Data Scientist and Telecommunications Engineer. Experience in Advanced Analytics, Data Science and Orchestration through BigData platforms, as well as Product Delivery and Customer Support. Exploration, statistics, machine learning and data visualization with high variety of tools and programming languages.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022

Santiago, Chile

2015

Caracas, Venezuela

DATA SCIENCE MAGISTER

Universidad del Desarrollo (SCL)

TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

Universidad Católica Andrés Bello (CCS, VEN)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



DATA SCIENTIST/ARCHITECT (GLOBANT)

Apr22-Current (SCL)

✓ Go-To-Market model Analytics and Data Architecture delivery.

DATA SCIENTIST (CENCOSUD FIDELIDAD S.A.)

Sept21-Apr22 (SCL)

√ Advanced Analytics for customer journey in Cencosud business areas: Supermarkets,

Retail, etc. Analytic models to characterize end-customer experience.

✓ NLP data processing and modelling. Sentiment and topic analysis.

- ✓ Customer segmentation using different clustering methods for commercial campaigns.
- ✓ Data Products design and implementation in Azure. DevOps

DATA SCIENTIST (WOM CHILE)

May21-Sept21 (SCL)

- ✓ Data mining for Network Performance and mobile operator services. Statistical analysis and exploration. Data Visualization with Python and Tableau.
- √ Feature engineering, KPI design from raw data. Clustering, segmentation of network elements and end-customers.
- ✓ Design and implementation of automatic data processing systems and integrations.

SERVICE EXPERIENCE TECH. DIRECTOR (HUAWEI CHILE)

Data Engineering, Analysis and Insight

- ✓ Data mining through SQL queries for customer experience insights on mobile and fixed networks. Report data visualization with Python libraries and Tableau. Data cleaning and integration with external systems. Data integrity analysis.
- ✓ Network and end-user KQIs / KPIs failure analysis, signaling flows and CS/PS GUL protocols.

Implementation/Support for Software/Hardware

✓ Data mining through SQL queries for customer experience insights on mobile and fixed networks. Report data visualization with Python libraries and Tableau. Data cleaning and integration with external systems. Data integrity analysis.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCES

2014-2016 (CCS, VEN)

- ✓ TX&Design Engineer. Huawei Venezuela. 2015-2016
- ✓ Telecom University Professor. UCAB Venezuela. 2015-2016
- ✓ Product Engineer. ICO C.A. Venezuela. 2014-2015
- ✓ NOC Operator Intern. DESCA Venezuela. 2014